<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematics on CryptoPatrick | Seamless Global Nature</title>
    <link>/tags/mathematics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematics on CryptoPatrick | Seamless Global Nature</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cipher: Atbash</title>
      <link>/posts/20220915_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220915_01/</guid>
      <description>Credit: FotoRieth
&amp;ldquo;And after them the king of Sheshach shall drink.&amp;rdquo;
It might not be obvious, but Sheshach in that phrase is actually one of the earliest examples of secret code, in this case for the name: Babylon.
In this brief post I will go over Atbash, an old substitution cipher technique from around 500 B.C.
The name Atbash could deride from the story of Babel, where God confused the speech of people, as punishment for trying to build a tower all the way to heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cipher: Caesar</title>
      <link>/posts/20220915_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220915_04/</guid>
      <description>The Greek historian Polybius
Gaius Julius Caesar needs little introduction. The Roman general and politician became dictator of Rome. He was assasinated in 44 B.C. by fellow senators who feared he was becoming too powerful .
In his book Gallic Wars, Julis Caesar describes a method of encipherment that has come to be known as The Caesar Cipher.
The Ciphering Process The Caesar Cipher is an example of a shift cipher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cipher: Nomenclator</title>
      <link>/posts/20220915_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220915_05/</guid>
      <description>A Simple Code Example Let&amp;rsquo;s try to write a simple Nomenclator program.
The following program makes a lot of assumptions on the input provided to the ciphering function. The program is only meant to illustrate the fundamental idea of the cipher.
1use std::collections::HashMap; 2 3struct Nomenclator { 4 nc: HashMap&amp;lt;&amp;amp;str, &amp;amp;str&amp;gt;, 5} 6 7 8impl Nomenclator { 9 pub fn encipher(&amp;amp;self, message: &amp;amp;str) -&amp;gt; String { 10 let mut res = String::new(); 11 12 for letter in message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cipher: Polybius&#39; checkerboard</title>
      <link>/posts/20220915_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220915_03/</guid>
      <description>The Greek historian Polybius
The Polybius Checkerboard, named after Greek historian Polybius, is an example of a substitution cipher from around 205-123 B.C. .
Polybius was the first to propose a method of substituting different two-digit numbers for a letter in an alphabet. Hence, the Polybius&amp;rsquo; Checkerboard is an early example of a substitution cipher.
Polybius&amp;rsquo; Checkerboard A Polybius&amp;rsquo; checkerboard looks almost like a like a checkerboard. Each square holds a letter and we can locate a letter on the checkerboard by crossreferencing a unique row and column number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cipher: Spartan Scytale</title>
      <link>/posts/20220915_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220915_02/</guid>
      <description>Credit: FotoRieth
The Spartan Scytale was communication device used by the military of Sparta.
The Scytale is an example of a transposition cipher and it dates from around 500 B.C. .
The Ciphering Process Image: Spartan Scytale
Setup:
The sender of the message takes a strip of parchement (paper) and wrapps it around a cylindrical rod. Write plaintext message:
The sender writes the message line by line, and parallel to the rod&amp;rsquo;s axis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
